<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on DJMol Docs</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on DJMol Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chaper 1</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter1/</guid><description>Chapter 1: Introduction DJMol is an ongoing open source (licensed with GPL v3 or later) ‘Modeling Platform’ project and it is architectured for performing various simulations in computational materials science / chemistry. It is a free, object-oriented software developed by IKST, (Indo-Korea Science and Technology Centre, 17/1, Bellary Rd, Yashoda Nagar, Yelahanka, Bengaluru, Karnataka 560064), Bangalore.
In its core level, DJMol is integrated with widely accepted and open source (GPL/LGPL ) computational software, such as,</description></item><item><title>Chaper 2</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter2/</guid><description>Chapter 2: DFTB+ Calculations Here we illustrate some standard procedures that can be performed by the DFTB+ program in conjunction with DJMol platform. At present there are three distinct file types can be opened for DFTB+ calculations, viz., [1] dftb_in.hsd, &amp;lt;.xyz&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;.gen&amp;gt; files. The first one is the default unique file type for the program and the last two file extensions can be converted into &amp;lt;dftb_in.hsd&amp;gt; file by using a script writer (see below section).</description></item><item><title>Chaper 3</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter3/</guid><description>Modeling with Siesta This add-on is mainly used for performing small to moderate level Siesta DFT calculations (with hundred of atoms). For larger calculations users are advised to use cluster/GCP machines with MPI parallel binaries. This add-on is equipped with OpenMP so that multi core machines can be used for its calculations, if it is found necessary. Note that Siesta 4.1 version is used in this add-on.
At the present version all molecular structural data and non Z-matrix styled crystalline FDF data is supported by this add-on.</description></item><item><title>Chaper 4</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter4/</guid><description>OpenMD Simulations OpenMD add-on is aimed to perform MD calculations with OpenMD binary/scripts. This tool has four parts, (1), Viewer (2), Editor (3), Terminal and, (4), Utilities.
Figure 4.1: Front end of the OpenMD add-on tool displays Ag nanoparticle obtained using OpenMD.
In viewer a normal XYZ file can be viewed (usually it is obtained from OMD dump file by using a converter, Dump2XYZ). All other standard Jmol view facilities are available here.</description></item><item><title>Chaper 5</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter5/</guid><description>Python scripting with ASE To demonstrate ASE scripting within the platform, we must create a Python project:
File ➤ New Project ➤ Python ➤ Python Project – Ant
and save this in a suitable directory. We name the main class as &amp;lt;ASEdemo&amp;gt;.
Figure 5.1: Setting up a Python ASE project in the DJMol application.
Figure 5.2: A script window displays an ASE script.
The purpose of this ASE calculation is to obtain the phonon dispersion for bulk aluminum using a 7×7×7 supercell within effective medium theory (EMT as it is implemented in ASE).</description></item><item><title>Chaper 6</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter6/</guid><description>Tools of DJMol Tools are generally calculator independent (add-on) modules which can assist some steps in the modeling.
Some of the important Tools are described below.
[1] Analysing Point Group DJMol use a point group analyzer and from this one can easily find the point group of a molecule and its subgroups. It can also tell the next possible point group within a specified error-bar. This module can be invoked by:</description></item><item><title>Chaper 7</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter7/</guid><description>Architecture of the Program Software Architecture
In practice, computational materials science research encompasses three distinctive steps, viz. (1), constructing the geometrical data or structure of the system (2), performing computations and, (3), obtaining results by the post processing of calculated data. All these steps can be effectively coupled by means of modeling platform such that a user can create, visualize, and share various input data files and run it with appropriate programs to obtain output data to analyze the results.</description></item><item><title>Chaper 8</title><link>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://djmolprogram.github.io/documentation/chapter8/</guid><description>Software Applications Demonstration of DJMol - 1
UV-Visible Spectrum of Silver Nanocluster using DFTB+
To demonstrate the basic functionality of the software, here we describe how an UV-Visible spectrum of a silver nanocluster can be calculated using DFTB+ code in conjunction with the DJMol software. There are three steps to calculate the spectrum, viz. (1) Obtain the structure of Ag nanocluster, (2) Optimize the structure and create the corresponding HSD file for the TD-DFTB calculation and, (3) Plot the convoluted Spectrum data.</description></item></channel></rss>